Townsend Saunders III

OR 97333 | linkedin.com/in/townsendsaunders3 | townsend.saunders3@gmail.com

Summary

Lead Data Scientist with 4.5 years of experience in data science, machine learning, and project management within the manufacturing and materials industry. Specialized in optimizing business operations, most notably demonstrated by the standardization of 95% of inventory across 75 brands at Reliance Inc. Skilled in mentoring, building relationships, and bridging the gap between technical teams and non-technical stakeholders. 1 of 4 Spring 2019 graduates from UC Berkeley with a degree in Engineering Mathematics in Statistics.

Skills

Languages: Python, SQL, Java, C, Ruby, Julia, JavaScript, R, Django, Flask, React, MATLAB

ML: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn, Pandas, PySpark, Hugging Face, Polars, statsmodels, NLTK, Airflow

Amazon Web Services AWS: SageMaker, Lambda, Fargate, S3, Glue, ECS, ECR

Tools: Azure, Databricks, Jupyter, Streamlit, GitHub, Docker, Snowflake, Google Ads, Tableau, Microsoft Power BI, CI/CD

AI: Open AI, ChatGPT, GPT-4, GPT-4o, Dall-E 3, Llama, RAG, Deep Learning, Neural Networks, Apple MLX

Work Experience

Lead Data Scientist

Adomly

Sep 2023 - Present

- Led AI-driven initiatives using Dall-E 3, resulting in a 261% increase in impressions and a 57% boost in CTR within 1 month, significantly improving customer engagement metrics.
- Managed cross-functional projects and developed interactive profit vs. cost dashboards using Python and Streamlit, enabling real-time what-if analysis.

Senior Data Scientist

Reliance Inc.

Aug 2022 - Sep 2023

• **Delivered 500+ Random Forest models** that standardized **95**% of Reliance's inventory, enabling efficient inventory sharing across **75 brands, 315 locations, and 12 countries**.

Data Scientist

Reliance Inc.

May 2021 – Aug 2022

 Deployed a self-serve forecasting tool for generating ML models across 10M+ combinations, optimizing inventory management for \$18B+ in products.

Business Systems Analyst

Reliance Inc.

Feb 2020 - May 2021

 Accounted for \$3M+ of unknown purchases by implementing a probabilistic matching algorithm that cleaned dirty supplier financial data.

Proiects

- Personal LLM AI Chatbot: Created a Python-based Chatbot using GPT-3.5 and Streamlit.
- Al Gender Race Bias Research: Found significant bias in GPT-40 product recommendations based on gender/race.

Education

University of California, Berkeley

B.S. Engineering Mathematics and Statistics, 2015-2019

- Undergraduate Scholarship Recipient
- Kappa Alpha Order, IM Sports (Soccer, Basketball, Football, Wrestling), Ceramics

Volunteer

- Live for others: Helped run charity volleyball tournament to help fund synovial sarcoma pediatric cancer research.
- Relay for Life: Raised \$1000 for breast cancer research